<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Label drug="Aldactone" setid="0fed2822-3a03-4b64-9857-c682fcd462bc">
<Text><Section name="DOSAGE &amp; ADMINISTRATION SECTION" id="34068-7">
2 DOSAGE AND ADMINISTRATION 

 Heart Failure: Initiate treatment at 25 mg once daily ( 2.2 ). 
 Hypertension: Initiate treatment at 25 to 100 mg daily in either single or divided doses ( 2.3 ). 
 Edema: Initiate therapy in a hospital setting and titrate slowly. The recommended initial daily dose is 100 mg in single or divided doses ( 2.3 ). 
 Primary hyperaldosteronism: Initiate treatement at 100 to 400 mg in preparation for surgery. In patients unsuitable for surgery use the lowest effective dosage determined for the individual patient ( 2.4 ). 

 2.1 General Considerations 

 ALDACTONE can be taken with or without food, but should be taken consistently with respect to food [see Clinical Pharmacology (12.3) ] . 

 2.2 Treatment of Heart Failure 

 In patients with serum potassium ≤5.0 mEq/L and eGFR &gt;50 mL/min/1.73 m 2 , initiate treatment at 25 mg once daily. Patients who tolerate 25 mg once daily may have their dosage increased to 50 mg once daily as clinically indicated. Patients who develop hyperkalemia on 25 mg once daily may have their dosage reduced to 25 mg every other day [see Warnings and Precautions (5.1) ] . In patients with an eGFR between 30 and 50 mL/min/1.73 m 2 , consider initiating therapy at 25 mg every other day because of the risk of hyperkalemia [see Use in Specific Populations (8.6) ]. 

 2.3 Treatment of Essential Hypertension 

 The recommended initial daily dose is 25 to 100 mg of ALDACTONE administered in either single or divided doses is recommended. Dosage can be titrated at two-week intervals. Doses greater than 100 mg/day generally do not provide additional reductions in blood pressure. 

 2.4 Treatment of Edema 

 In patients with cirrhosis, initiate therapy in a hospital setting and titrate slowly [see Use in Specific Populations (8.7) ] . The recommended initial daily dosage is 100 mg of ALDACTONE administered in either single or divided doses, but may range from 25 to 200 mg daily. When given as the sole agent for diuresis, administer for at least five days before increasing dose to obtain desired effect. 

 2.5 Treatment of Primary Hyperaldosteronism 

 Administer ALDACTONE in doses of 100 to 400 mg daily in preparation for surgery. For patients who are considered unsuitable for surgery, ALDACTONE can be used as long-term maintenance therapy at the lowest effective dosage determined for the individual patient.</Section>
<Section name="CONTRAINDICATIONS SECTION" id="34070-3">
4 CONTRAINDICATIONS 

 ALDACTONE is contraindicated in the patients with: 

 Hyperkalemia 
 Addison's disease 
 Concomitant use of eplerenone 

 ALDACTONE is contraindicated in patients with ( 4 ): 

 Hyperkalemia 
 Addison's disease 
 Concomitant use of eplerenone</Section>
<Section name="WARNINGS AND PRECAUTIONS SECTION" id="43685-7">
5 WARNINGS AND PRECAUTIONS 

 Hyperkalemia: Monitor serum potassium within one week of initation and regularly therafter ( 5.1 ). 
 Hypotension and Worsening Renal Function: Motor volume status and renal function periodically ( 5.2 ). 
 Electrolyte and Metabolic Abnormalities: Monitor serum electrolytes, uric acid and blood glucose periodically ( 5.3 ). 
 Gynecomastia: ALDACTONE can cause gynecomastia ( 5.4 ). 

 5.1 Hyperkalemia 

 ALDACTONE can cause hyperkalemia. This risk is increased by impaired renal function or concomitant potassium supplementation, potassium-containing salt substitutes or drugs that increase potassium, such as angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors and angiotensin receptor blockers [see Drug Interactions (7.1) ] . 
 Monitor serum potassium within 1 week of initiation or titration of ALDACTONE and regularly thereafter. More frequent monitoring may be needed when ALDACTONE is given with other drugs that cause hyperkalemia or in patients with impaired renal function. 
 If hyperkalemia occurs, decrease the dose or discontinue ALDACTONE and treat hyperkalemia. 

 5.2 Hypotension and Worsening Renal Function 

 Excessive diuresis may cause symptomatic dehydration, hypotension and worsening renal function, particularly in salt-depleted patients or those taking angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors and angiotensin II receptor blockers. Worsening of renal function can also occur with concomitant use of nephrotoxic drugs (e.g., aminoglycosides, cisplatin, and NSAIDs). Monitor volume status and renal function periodically. 

 5.3 Electrolyte and Metabolic Abnormalities 

 In addition to causing hyperkalemia, ALDACTONE can cause hyponatremia, hypomagnesemia, hypocalcemia, hypochloremic alkalosis, and hyperglycemia. Asymptomatic hyperuricemia can occur and rarely gout is precipitated. Monitor serum electrolytes, uric acid and blood glucose periodically. 

 5.4 Gynecomastia 

 ALDACTONE can cause gynecomastia. In RALES, patients with heart failure treated with a mean dose of 26 mg of spironolactone once daily, about 9% of the male subjects developed gynecomastia. The risk of gynecomastia increases in a dose-dependent manner with an onset that varies widely from 1–2 months to over a year. Gynecomastia is usually reversible.</Section>
<Section name="DRUG INTERACTIONS SECTION" id="34073-7">
7 DRUG INTERACTIONS 

 Agents increasing serum potassium: Concomitant administration can lead to hyperkalemia ( 5.1 , 7.1 ). 
 Lithium: Increased risk of lithium toxicity ( 7.2 ). 
 NSAIDs: May reduce the diuretic, natriuretic and antihypertensive effect of ALDACTONE ( 7.3 ). 
 Digoxin: ALDACTONE can interfere with radioimmunologic assays of digoxin exposure ( 7.4 ). 
 Cholestyramine: Hyperkalemic metabolic acidosis has been reported with concomitant use ( 7.5 ). 
 Acetylsalicylic Acid (ASA): ASA may reduce the efficacy of ALDACTONE ( 7.6 ). 

 7.1 Drugs and Supplements Increasing Serum Potassium 

 Concomitant administration of ALDACTONE with potassium supplementation or drugs that can increase potassium may lead to severe hyperkalemia. In general, discontinue potassium supplementation in heart failure patients who start ALDACTONE [see Warnings and Precautions (5.1) and Clinical Pharmacology (12.3) ] . Check serum potassium levels when ACE inhibitor or ARB therapy is altered in patients receiving ALDACTONE. 
 Examples of drugs that can increase potassium include: 

 ACE inhibitors 
 angiotensin receptor blockers 
 non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) 
 heparin and low molecular weight heparin 
 trimethoprim 

 7.2 Lithium 

 Like other diuretics, ALDACTONE reduces the renal clearance of lithium, thus increasing the risk of lithium toxicity. Monitor lithium levels periodically when ALDACTONE is coadministered [see Clinical Pharmacology (12.3) ] . 

 7.3 Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) 

 In some patients, the administration of an NSAID can reduce the diuretic, natriuretic, and antihypertensive effect of diuretics. Therefore, when ALDACTONE and NSAIDs are used concomitantly, monitor closely to determine if the desired effect of the diuretic is obtained [see Clinical Pharmacology (12.3) ] . 

 7.4 Digoxin 

 Spironolactone and its metabolites interfere with radioimmunoassays for digoxin and increase the apparent exposure to digoxin. It is unknown to what extent, if any, spironolactone may increase actual digoxin exposure. In patients taking concomitant digoxin, use an assay that does not interact with spironolactone. 

 7.5 Cholestyramine 

 Hyperkalemic metabolic acidosis has been reported in patients given ALDACTONE concurrently with cholestyramine. 

 7.6 Acetylsalicylic Acid 

 Acetylsalicylic acid may reduce the efficacy of spironolactone. Therefore, when ALDACTONE and acetylsalicylic acid are used concomitantly, ALDACTONE may need to be titrated to higher maintenance dose and the patient should be observed closely to determine if the desired effect is obtained [see Clinical Pharmacology (12.3) ] .</Section>
</Text><Sentences>
<Sentence id="1" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE in a dosage ranging from 25 mg to 100 mg daily is useful in treating a diuretic-induced hypokalemia , when oral potassium supplements or other potassium-sparing regimens are considered inappropriate .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="2" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE may also be given with diuretics that act more proximally in the renal tubule or with other antihypertensive agents .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="3" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>Because of the additive effect of ALDACTONE when administered concurrently with such diuretics , an enhanced diuresis usually begins on the first day of combined treatment , combined therapy is indicated when more rapid diuresis is desired .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M1" type="Trigger" span="15 15" str="additive effect"/>
<Mention id="M2" type="Precipitant" span="85 9" str="diuretics" code="N0000029125"/>
<Mention id="M3" type="SpecificInteraction" span="100 17" str="enhanced diuresis" code="162182005: Diuresis (finding)"/>
<Interaction id="I1" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M1" precipitant="M2" effect="M3"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="4" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>If , after five days , an adequate diuretic response to ALDACTONE has not occurred , a second diuretic that acts more proximally in the renal tubule may be added to the regimen .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="5" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34070-3">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE is contraindicated for patients with anuria , acute renal insufficiency , significant impairment of renal excretory function , hyperkalemia , Addison 's disease , and with concomitant use of eplerenone .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M4" type="Trigger" span="13 15" str="contraindicated"/>
<Mention id="M5" type="Precipitant" span="201 10" str="eplerenone" code="N0000010111"/>
<Interaction id="I2" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M4" precipitant="M5"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="6" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE , when used with ACE inhibitors or indomethacin , even in the presence of a diuretic , has been associated with severe hyperkalemia .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M9" type="Trigger" span="106 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M7" type="Precipitant" span="27 14" str="ACE inhibitors" code="N0000029130"/>
<Mention id="M11" type="SpecificInteraction" span="122 19" str="severe hyperkalemia" code="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M10" type="Precipitant" span="45 12" str="indomethacin" code="N0000006990"/>
<Interaction id="I3" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M9" precipitant="M7" effect="M11"/>
<Interaction id="I4" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M9" precipitant="M10" effect="M11"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="6" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE , when used with ACE inhibitors or indomethacin , even in the presence of a diuretic , has been associated with severe hyperkalemia .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M15" type="Trigger" span="106 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M13" type="Precipitant" span="27 14" str="ACE inhibitors" code="N0000029130"/>
<Mention id="M17" type="SpecificInteraction" span="122 19" str="severe hyperkalemia" code="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M16" type="Precipitant" span="45 12" str="indomethacin" code="N0000006990"/>
<Interaction id="I5" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M13" effect="M17"/>
<Interaction id="I6" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M16" effect="M17"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="7" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE should not be administered concurrently with other potassium-sparing diuretics .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M18" type="Trigger" span="10 26" str="should not be administered"/>
<Mention id="M19" type="Precipitant" span="61 27" str="potassium-sparing diuretics" code="N0000175418"/>
<Interaction id="I7" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M18" precipitant="M19"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="8" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>Concomitant administration of ALDACTONE with the following drugs or potassium sources may lead to severe hyperkalemia : .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="9" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>Potassium supplementation , either in the form of medication or as a diet rich in potassium , should not ordinarily be given in association with ALDACTONE therapy .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M20" type="Trigger" span="94 10;116 8" str="should not | be given"/>
<Mention id="M21" type="Precipitant" span="82 9" str="potassium" code="N0000175600"/>
<Interaction id="I8" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M20" precipitant="M21"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="10" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Combination of NSAIDs, e.g., indomethacin, with potassium-sparing diuretics has been associated with severe hyperkalemia.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M25" type="Trigger" span="85 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M23" type="Precipitant" span="29 12" str="indomethacin" code="N0000006990"/>
<Mention id="M27" type="SpecificInteraction" span="101 19" str="severe hyperkalemia" code="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M26" type="Precipitant" span="15 6" str="NSAIDs" code="N0000175722"/>
<Interaction id="I9" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M25" precipitant="M23" effect="M27"/>
<Interaction id="I10" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M25" precipitant="M26" effect="M27"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="10" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Combination of NSAIDs, e.g., indomethacin, with potassium-sparing diuretics has been associated with severe hyperkalemia.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M31" type="Trigger" span="85 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M29" type="Precipitant" span="29 12" str="indomethacin" code="N0000006990"/>
<Mention id="M33" type="SpecificInteraction" span="101 19" str="severe hyperkalemia" code="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M32" type="Precipitant" span="15 6" str="NSAIDs" code="N0000175722"/>
<Interaction id="I11" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M31" precipitant="M29" effect="M33"/>
<Interaction id="I12" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M31" precipitant="M32" effect="M33"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="11" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Concomitant administration may lead to severe hyperkalemia.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="12" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Concomitant administration of ACE inhibitors with potassium-sparing diuretics has been associated with severe hyperkalemia.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M34" type="Trigger" span="87 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M35" type="Precipitant" span="30 14" str="ACE inhibitors" code="N0000029130"/>
<Mention id="M36" type="SpecificInteraction" span="103 19" str="severe hyperkalemia" code="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<Interaction id="I13" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M34" precipitant="M35" effect="M36"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="13" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Diuretic agents reduce the renal clearance of lithium and add a high risk of lithium toxicity.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M37" type="Trigger" span="16 6;27 15" str="reduce | renal clearance"/>
<Mention id="M38" type="Precipitant" span="46 7" str="lithium" code="N0000147892"/>
<Interaction id="I14" type="Pharmacokinetic interaction" trigger="M37" precipitant="M38" effect="C54357"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="14" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>In some patients, the administration of an NSAID can reduce the diuretic, natriuretic, and antihypertensive effect of loop, potassium-sparing, and thiazide diuretics.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M39" type="Trigger" span="53 6;108 6" str="reduce | effect"/>
<Mention id="M40" type="Precipitant" span="43 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M41" type="SpecificInteraction" span="53 6;64 8;108 6" str="reduce | diuretic | effect " code="76569007: Anti-diuresis (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M42" type="SpecificInteraction" span="53 6;74 11;108 6" str=" reduce | natriuretic | effect " code=""/>
<Mention id="M43" type="SpecificInteraction" span="53 6;91 23" str=" reduce | antihypertensive effect" code=""/>
<Interaction id="I15" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M39" precipitant="M40" effect="M41;M42;M43"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="15" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Intensified electrolyte depletion, particularly hypokalemia, may occur.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="16" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>It may be necessary to reduce the maintenance and digitalization doses when ALDACTONE is administered, and the patient should be carefully monitored to avoid over- or under-digitalization.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="17" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Lithium generally should not be given with diuretics.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M44" type="Trigger" span="18 19" str="should not be given"/>
<Mention id="M45" type="Precipitant" span="0 7" str="Lithium" code="N0000147892"/>
<Interaction id="I16" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M44" precipitant="M45"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="18" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Possible increased responsiveness to the muscle relaxant may result.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="19" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Potentiation of orthostatic hypotension may occur.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="20" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Therefore, caution should be exercised in the management of patients subjected to regional or general anesthesia while they are being treated with ALDACTONE.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="21" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>This may result in increased serum digoxin levels and subsequent digitalis toxicity.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="22" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>A dose-related ( above 20 mg/kg/day ) incidence of myelocytic leukemia was observed in rats fed daily doses of potassium canrenoate ( a compound chemically similar to ALDACTONE and whose primary metabolite , canrenone , is also a major product of ALDACTONE in man ) for a period of one year .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="23" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE ( 100 mg/kg/day ) , administered i.p. to female mice during a two-week cohabitation period with untreated males , decreased the number of mated mice that conceived ( effect shown to be caused by an inhibition of ovulation ) and decreased the number of implanted embryos in those that became pregnant ( effect shown to be caused by an inhibition of implantation ) , and at 200 mg/kg , also increased the latency period to mating .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="24" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE has been shown to increase the half-life of digoxin .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M46" type="Trigger" span="28 8;41 9" str="increase | half-life"/>
<Mention id="M47" type="Precipitant" span="54 7" str="digoxin" code="N0000005903"/>
<Interaction id="I17" type="Pharmacokinetic interaction" trigger="M46" precipitant="M47" effect="C54611"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="25" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>ALDACTONE reduces the vascular responsiveness to norepinephrine .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M48" type="Trigger" span="10 7;31 14" str="reduces | responsiveness"/>
<Mention id="M49" type="Precipitant" span="49 14" str="norepinephrine" code="N0000007426"/>
<Mention id="M50" type="SpecificInteraction" span="10 35" str="reduces the vascular responsiveness" code="NO MAP"/>
<Interaction id="I18" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M48" precipitant="M49" effect="M50"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="26" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Because of its antiandrogenic activity and the requirement of testosterone for male morphogenesis , ALDACTONE may have the potential for adversely affecting sex differentiation of the male during embryogenesis .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="27" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Canrenone , a major ( and active ) metabolite of ALDACTONE , appears in human breast milk .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="28" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Consequently , no potassium supplement should ordinarily be given with ALDACTONE .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M51" type="Trigger" span="15 2;39 6;57 8" str="no | should | be given"/>
<Mention id="M52" type="Precipitant" span="18 20" str="potassium supplement" code="N0000175600"/>
<Interaction id="I19" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M51" precipitant="M52"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="29" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Dilutional hyponatremia , manifested by dryness of the mouth , thirst , lethargy , and drowsiness , and confirmed by a low serum sodium level , may be caused or aggravated , especially when ALDACTONE is administered in combination with other diuretics , and dilutional hyponatremia may occur in edematous patients in hot weather , appropriate therapy is water restriction rather than administration of sodium , except in rare instances when the hyponatremia is life-threatening .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M53" type="Trigger" span="151 6" str="caused "/>
<Mention id="M54" type="Trigger" span="161 10" str=" aggravated"/>
<Mention id="M55" type="Precipitant" span="242 9" str="diuretics" code="N0000029125"/>
<Mention id="M56" type="SpecificInteraction" span="0 23" str="Dilutional hyponatremia " code="307201006:  Dilutional hyponatremia (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M57" type="SpecificInteraction" span="40 20" str=" dryness of the mouth " code=" 87715008:  Xerostomia (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M58" type="SpecificInteraction" span="63 6" str=" thirst " code=" 249477003: Increased thirst (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M59" type="SpecificInteraction" span="72 8" str=" lethargy " code=" 214264003:  Lethargy (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M60" type="SpecificInteraction" span="87 10" str=" drowsiness " code=" 271782001:  Drowsy (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M61" type="SpecificInteraction" span="119 22" str=" low serum sodium level" code=" 89627008: Hyponatremia (disorder)"/>
<Interaction id="I20" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M53;M54" precipitant="M55" effect="M56;M57;M58;M59;M60;M61"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="30" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Hyperkalemic metabolic acidosis has been reported in patients given ALDACTONE concurrently with cholestyramine .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M64" type="SpecificInteraction" span="0 31" str="Hyperkalemic metabolic acidosis" code="237847005: Hyperkalemic acidosis (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M63" type="Precipitant" span="96 14" str="cholestyramine" code="N0000007079"/>
<Interaction id="I21" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M64" precipitant="M63" effect="M64"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="31" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>In the absence of metabolic activation , neither ALDACTONE nor potassium canrenoate has been shown to be mutagenic in mammalian tests in vitro .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="32" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Neither ALDACTONE nor potassium canrenoate produced mutagenic effects in tests using bacteria or yeast .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="33" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Patients who receive ALDACTONE should be advised to avoid potassium supplements and foods containing high levels of potassium , including salt substitutes .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M65" type="Trigger" span="52 5" str="avoid"/>
<Mention id="M66" type="Precipitant" span="58 9" str="potassium" code="N0000175600"/>
<Interaction id="I22" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M65" precipitant="M66"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="34" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Several reports of possible interference with digoxin radioimmunoassay by ALDACTONE , or its metabolites , have appeared in the literature .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="35" LabelDrug="Aldactone" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Therefore , when ALDACTONE and NSAIDs are used concomitantly , the patient should be observed closely to determine if the desired effect of the diuretic is obtained .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M67" type="Trigger" span="75 18" str="should be observed"/>
<Mention id="M68" type="Precipitant" span="31 6" str="NSAIDs" code="N0000175722"/>
<Interaction id="I23" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M67" precipitant="M68"/>
</Sentence>
</Sentences>
<LabelInteractions><LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect=" 214264003:  Lethargy (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect=" 249477003: Increased thirst (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect=" 271782001:  Drowsy (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect=" 87715008:  Xerostomia (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect=" 89627008: Hyponatremia (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect="162182005: Diuresis (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000029125" effect="307201006:  Dilutional hyponatremia (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="eplerenone" precipitantCode="N0000010111"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="ace inhibitors" precipitantCode="N0000029130" effect="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="indomethacin" precipitantCode="N0000006990" effect="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="potassium-sparing diuretics" precipitantCode="N0000175418"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="potassium" precipitantCode="N0000175600"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="nsaids" precipitantCode="N0000175722" effect="14140009: Hyperkalemia (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="nsaids" precipitantCode="N0000175722"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacokinetic interaction" precipitant="lithium" precipitantCode="N0000147892" effect="C54357"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="lithium" precipitantCode="N0000147892"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="nsaid" precipitantCode="N0000175722" effect="76569007: Anti-diuresis (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacokinetic interaction" precipitant="digoxin" precipitantCode="N0000005903" effect="C54611"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="norepinephrine" precipitantCode="N0000007426" effect="NO MAP"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="potassium supplement" precipitantCode="N0000175600"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="cholestyramine" precipitantCode="N0000007079" effect="237847005: Hyperkalemic acidosis (disorder)"/>

</LabelInteractions></Label>