<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Label drug="Adenocard" setid="f0e32589-dad9-4887-8481-bcf7f6618466">
<Text><Section name="CONTRAINDICATIONS SECTION" id="34070-3">
Contraindications 

 Intravenous Adenocard (adenosine injection) is contraindicated in: 

 Second- or third-degree A-V block (except in patients with a functioning artificial pacemaker). 
 Sinus node disease, such as sick sinus syndrome or symptomatic bradycardia (except in patients with a functioning artificial pacemaker). 
 Known hypersensitivity to adenosine.</Section>
<Section name="WARNINGS SECTION" id="34071-1">
Warnings 

 Heart Block 

 Adenocard (adenosine injection) exerts its effect by decreasing conduction through the A-V node and may produce a short lasting first-, second- or third-degree heart block. Appropriate therapy should be instituted as needed. Patients who develop high-level block on one dose of Adenocard should not be given additional doses. Because of the very short half-life of adenosine, these effects are generally self-limiting. Appropriate resuscitative measures should be available. 
 Transient or prolonged episodes of asystole have been reported with fatal outcomes in some cases. Rarely, ventricular fibrillation has been reported following Adenocard administration, including both resuscitated and fatal events. In most instances, these cases were associated with the concomitant use of digoxin and, less frequently with digoxin and verapamil. Although no causal relationship or drug-drug interaction has been established, Adenocard should be used with caution in patients receiving digoxin or digoxin and verapamil in combination. 

 Arrhythmias at Time of Conversion 

 At the time of conversion to normal sinus rhythm, a variety of new rhythms may appear on the electrocardiogram. They generally last only a few seconds without intervention, and may take the form of premature ventricular contractions, atrial premature contractions, atrial fibrillation, sinus bradycardia, sinus tachycardia, skipped beats, and varying degrees of A-V nodal block. Such findings were seen in 55% of patients. 

 Bronchoconstriction 

 Adenocard (adenosine injection) is a respiratory stimulant (probably through activation of carotid body chemoreceptors) and intravenous administration in man has been shown to increase minute ventilation (Ve) and reduce arterial PCO 2 causing respiratory alkalosis. 
 Adenosine administered by inhalation has been reported to cause bronchoconstriction in asthmatic patients, presumably due to mast cell degranulation and histamine release. These effects have not been observed in normal subjects. Adenocard has been administered to a limited number of patients with asthma and mild to moderate exacerbation of their symptoms has been reported. Respiratory compromise has occurred during adenosine infusion in patients with obstructive pulmonary disease. Adenocard should be used with caution in patients with obstructive lung disease not associated with bronchoconstriction (e.g., emphysema, bronchitis, etc.) and should be avoided in patients with bronchoconstriction or bronchospasm (e.g., asthma). Adenocard should be discontinued in any patient who develops severe respiratory difficulties.</Section>
<Section name="PRECAUTIONS SECTION" id="42232-9">
Precautions 

 Drug Interactions 

 Intravenous Adenocard (adenosine injection) has been effectively administered in the presence of other cardioactive drugs, such as quinidine, beta-adrenergic blocking agents, calcium channel blocking agents, and angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors, without any change in the adverse reaction profile. Digoxin and verapamil use may be rarely associated with ventricular fibrillation when combined with Adenocard (see 
 Warnings 
 ). Because of the potential for additive or synergistic depressant effects on the SA and AV nodes, however, Adenocard should be used with caution in the presence of these agents. The use of Adenocard in patients receiving digitalis may be rarely associated with ventricular fibrillation (see 
 Warnings 
 ). 
 The effects of adenosine are antagonized by methylxanthines such as caffeine and theophylline. In the presence of these methylxanthines, larger doses of adenosine may be required or adenosine may not be effective. Adenosine effects are potentiated by dipyridamole. Thus, smaller doses of adenosine may be effective in the presence of dipyridamole. Carbamazepine has been reported to increase the degree of heart block produced by other agents. As the primary effect of adenosine is to decrease conduction through the A-V node, higher degrees of heart block may be produced in the presence of carbamazepine. 

 Carcinogenesis, Mutagenesis, Impairment of Fertility 

 Studies in animals have not been performed to evaluate the carcinogenic potential of Adenocard (adenosine injection). Adenosine was negative for genotoxic potential in the Salmonella (Ames Test) and Mammalian Microsome Assay. 
 Adenosine, however, like other nucleosides at millimolar concentrations present for several doubling times of cells in culture, is known to produce a variety of chromosomal alterations. Fertility studies in animals have not been conducted with adenosine. 

 Pregnancy Category C 

 Animal reproduction studies have not been conducted with adenosine; nor have studies been performed in pregnant women. As adenosine is a naturally occurring material, widely dispersed throughout the body, no fetal effects would be anticipated. However, since it is not known whether Adenocard can cause fetal harm when administered to pregnant women, Adenocard should be used during pregnancy only if clearly needed. 

 Pediatric Use 

 No controlled studies have been conducted in pediatric patients to establish the safety and efficacy of Adenocard for the conversion of paroxysmal supraventricular tachycardia (PSVT). However, intravenous adenosine has been used for the treatment of PSVT in neonates, infants, children and adolescents (see 
 Dosage and Administration 
 ). 

 Geriatric Use 

 Clinical studies of Adenocard did not include sufficient numbers of subjects aged 65 and over to determine whether they respond differently from younger subjects. Other reported clinical experience has not identified differences in responses between elderly and younger patients. In general, Adenocard in geriatric patients should be used with caution since this population may have a diminished cardiac function, nodal dysfunction, concomitant diseases or drug therapy that may alter hemodynamic function and produce severe bradycardia or AV block.</Section>
<Section name="DOSAGE &amp; ADMINISTRATION SECTION" id="34068-7">
Dosage and Administration 

 For rapid bolus intravenous use only. 

 Adenocard (adenosine injection) should be given as a rapid bolus by the peripheral intravenous route. To be certain the solution reaches the systemic circulation, it should be administered either directly into a vein or, if given into an IV line, it should be given as close to the patient as possible and followed by a rapid saline flush. 

 Adult Patients 

 The dose recommendation is based on clinical studies with peripheral venous bolus dosing. Central venous (CVP or other) administration of Adenocard has not been systematically studied. 
 The recommended intravenous doses for adults are as follows: 

 Initial dose: 6 mg given as a rapid intravenous bolus (administered over a 1-2 second period). 

 Repeat administration: If the first dose does not result in elimination of the supraventricular tachycardia within 1-2 minutes, 12 mg should be given as a rapid intravenous bolus. This 12 mg dose may be repeated a second time if required. 

 Pediatric Patients 

 The dosages used in neonates, infants, children and adolescents were equivalent to those administered to adults on a weight basis. 
 Pediatric Patients with a Body Weight &lt; 50 kg: 

 Initial dose: Give 0.05 to 0.1 mg/kg as a rapid IV bolus given either centrally or peripherally. A saline flush should follow. 

 Repeat administration: If conversion of PSVT does not occur within 1-2 minutes, additional bolus injections of adenosine can be administered at incrementally higher doses, increasing the amount given by 0.05 to 0.1 mg/kg. Follow each bolus with a saline flush. This process should continue until sinus rhythm is established or a maximum single dose of 0.3 mg/kg is used. 
 Pediatric Patients with a Body Weight ≥ 50 kg: Administer the adult dose. 

 Doses greater than 12 mg are not recommended for adult and pediatric patients. 

 NOTE: Parenteral drug products should be inspected visually for particulate matter and discoloration prior to administration.</Section>
</Text><Sentences>
<Sentence id="511" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>Adenocard ( adenosine injection ) is a respiratory stimulant ( probably through activation of carotid body chemoreceptors ) and intravenous administration in man has been shown to increase minute ventilation ( Ve ) and reduce arterial PCO2 causing respiratory alkalosis .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="512" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Because of the potential for additive or synergistic depressant effects on the SA and AV nodes, however, Adenocard should be used with caution in the presence of these agents.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="513" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Carbamazepine has been reported to increase the degree of heart block produced by other agents.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M1" type="Trigger" span="35 19" str="increase the degree"/>
<Mention id="M2" type="Precipitant" span="0 13" str="Carbamazepine" code="N0000007470"/>
<Mention id="M3" type="SpecificInteraction" span="58 11" str="heart block" code="233916004: Heart block (disorder)"/>
<Interaction id="I1" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M1" precipitant="M2" effect="M3"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="514" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Digoxin and verapamil use may be rarely associated with ventricular fibrillation when combined with Adenocard (see Warnings ).</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M7" type="Trigger" span="40 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M5" type="Precipitant" span="0 7" str="Digoxin" code="N0000005903"/>
<Mention id="M9" type="SpecificInteraction" span="56 24" str="ventricular fibrillation" code="71908006: Ventricular fibrillation (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M8" type="Precipitant" span="12 9" str="verapamil" code="N0000007093"/>
<Interaction id="I2" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M7" precipitant="M5" effect="M9"/>
<Interaction id="I3" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M7" precipitant="M8" effect="M9"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="514" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Digoxin and verapamil use may be rarely associated with ventricular fibrillation when combined with Adenocard (see Warnings ).</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M13" type="Trigger" span="40 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M11" type="Precipitant" span="0 7" str="Digoxin" code="N0000005903"/>
<Mention id="M15" type="SpecificInteraction" span="56 24" str="ventricular fibrillation" code="71908006: Ventricular fibrillation (disorder)"/>
<Mention id="M14" type="Precipitant" span="12 9" str="verapamil" code="N0000007093"/>
<Interaction id="I4" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M13" precipitant="M11" effect="M15"/>
<Interaction id="I5" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M13" precipitant="M14" effect="M15"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="515" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Intravenous Adenocard (adenosine injection) has been effectively administered in the presence of other cardioactive drugs, such as quinidine, beta-adrenergic blocking agents, calcium channel blocking agents, and angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors, without any change in the adverse reaction profile.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="516" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>The use of Adenocard in patients receiving digitalis may be rarely associated with ventricular fibrillation (see Warnings ).</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M16" type="Trigger" span="67 15" str="associated with"/>
<Mention id="M17" type="Precipitant" span="43 9" str="digitalis" code="N0000147198"/>
<Mention id="M18" type="SpecificInteraction" span="83 24" str="ventricular fibrillation" code="71908006: Ventricular fibrillation (disorder)"/>
<Interaction id="I6" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M16" precipitant="M17" effect="M18"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="517" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Adenosine effects are potentiated by dipyridamole .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M19" type="Trigger" span="10 23" str="effects are potentiated"/>
<Mention id="M20" type="Precipitant" span="37 12" str="dipyridamole" code="N0000006853"/>
<Mention id="M21" type="SpecificInteraction" span="0 33" str="Adenosine effects are potentiated" code="NO MAP"/>
<Interaction id="I7" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M19" precipitant="M20" effect="M21"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="518" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>As the primary effect of adenosine is to decrease conduction through the A-V node , higher degrees of heart block may be produced in the presence of carbamazepine .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M22" type="Trigger" span="84 14" str="higher degrees"/>
<Mention id="M23" type="Precipitant" span="149 13" str="carbamazepine" code="N0000007470"/>
<Mention id="M24" type="SpecificInteraction" span="102 11" str="heart block" code="233916004: Heart block (disorder)"/>
<Interaction id="I8" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M22" precipitant="M23" effect="M24"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="519" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>In the presence of these methylxanthines , larger doses of adenosine may be required or adenosine may not be effective .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M25" type="Trigger" span="43 12;76 8" str="larger doses | required"/>
<Mention id="M26" type="Precipitant" span="25 15" str="methylxanthines" code="N0000179192"/>
<Mention id="M27" type="SpecificInteraction" span="88 30" str="adenosine may not be effective" code="NO MAP"/>
<Interaction id="I9" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M25" precipitant="M26" effect="M27"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="520" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Intravenous Adenocard ( adenosine injection ) has been effectively administered in the presence of other cardioactive drugs , such as quinidine , beta-adrenergic blocking agents , calcium channel blocking agents , and angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors , without any change in the adverse reaction profile .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="521" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>The effects of adenosine are antagonized by methylxanthines such as caffeine and theophylline .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M34" type="Trigger" span="4 7;29 11" str="effects | antagonized"/>
<Mention id="M29" type="Precipitant" span="68 8" str="caffeine" code="N0000006506"/>
<Mention id="M36" type="SpecificInteraction" span="4 36" str="effects of adenosine are antagonized" code="NO MAP"/>
<Mention id="M32" type="Precipitant" span="44 15" str="methylxanthines" code="N0000179192"/>
<Mention id="M35" type="Precipitant" span="81 12" str="theophylline" code="N0000007076"/>
<Interaction id="I10" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M34" precipitant="M29" effect="M36"/>
<Interaction id="I11" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M34" precipitant="M32" effect="M36"/>
<Interaction id="I12" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M34" precipitant="M35" effect="M36"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="521" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>The effects of adenosine are antagonized by methylxanthines such as caffeine and theophylline .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M43" type="Trigger" span="4 7;29 11" str="effects | antagonized"/>
<Mention id="M38" type="Precipitant" span="68 8" str="caffeine" code="N0000006506"/>
<Mention id="M45" type="SpecificInteraction" span="4 36" str="effects of adenosine are antagonized" code="NO MAP"/>
<Mention id="M41" type="Precipitant" span="44 15" str="methylxanthines" code="N0000179192"/>
<Mention id="M44" type="Precipitant" span="81 12" str="theophylline" code="N0000007076"/>
<Interaction id="I13" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M43" precipitant="M38" effect="M45"/>
<Interaction id="I14" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M43" precipitant="M41" effect="M45"/>
<Interaction id="I15" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M43" precipitant="M44" effect="M45"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="521" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>The effects of adenosine are antagonized by methylxanthines such as caffeine and theophylline .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M52" type="Trigger" span="4 7;29 11" str="effects | antagonized"/>
<Mention id="M47" type="Precipitant" span="68 8" str="caffeine" code="N0000006506"/>
<Mention id="M54" type="SpecificInteraction" span="4 36" str="effects of adenosine are antagonized" code="NO MAP"/>
<Mention id="M50" type="Precipitant" span="44 15" str="methylxanthines" code="N0000179192"/>
<Mention id="M53" type="Precipitant" span="81 12" str="theophylline" code="N0000007076"/>
<Interaction id="I16" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M52" precipitant="M47" effect="M54"/>
<Interaction id="I17" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M52" precipitant="M50" effect="M54"/>
<Interaction id="I18" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M52" precipitant="M53" effect="M54"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="522" LabelDrug="Adenocard" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Thus , smaller doses of adenosine may be effective in the presence of dipyridamole .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
</Sentences>
<LabelInteractions><LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="carbamazepine" precipitantCode="N0000007470" effect="233916004: Heart block (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="digoxin" precipitantCode="N0000005903" effect="71908006: Ventricular fibrillation (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="verapamil" precipitantCode="N0000007093" effect="71908006: Ventricular fibrillation (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="digitalis" precipitantCode="N0000147198" effect="71908006: Ventricular fibrillation (disorder)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="dipyridamole" precipitantCode="N0000006853" effect="NO MAP"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="methylxanthines" precipitantCode="N0000179192" effect="NO MAP"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="caffeine" precipitantCode="N0000006506" effect="NO MAP"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="theophylline" precipitantCode="N0000007076" effect="NO MAP"/>

</LabelInteractions></Label>