<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Label drug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" setid="6b17b98b-e06d-42ed-925f-69aa2699dead">
<Text><Section name="CONTRAINDICATIONS SECTION" id="34070-3">
CONTRAINDICATIONS 

 Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection is contraindicated in patients with idiopathic hypertrophic subaortic stenosis and in patients who have shown previous manifestations of hypersensitivity to dobutamine. 
 Solutions containing dextrose may be contraindicated in patients with known allergy to corn or corn products.</Section>
<Section name="WARNINGS SECTION" id="34071-1">
WARNINGS 

 Increase in Heart Rate or Blood Pressure 

 Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection may cause a marked increase in heart rate or blood pressure, especially systolic pressure. Approximately 10% of adult patients in clinical studies have had rate increases of 30 beats/minute or more, and about 7.5% have had a 50-mm Hg or greater increase in systolic pressure. Usually, reduction of dosage reverses these effects. Because dobutamine facilitates atrioventricular conduction, patients with atrial fibrillation are at risk of developing rapid ventricular response. Patients with preexisting hypertension appear to face an increased risk of developing an exaggerated pressor response. In patients who have atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response, a digitalis preparation should be used prior to institution of therapy with Dobutamine in D 5 W. 

 Ectopic Activity 

 Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection may precipitate or exacerbate ventricular ectopic activity, but it rarely has caused ventricular tachycardia. 

 Hypersensitivity 

 Reactions suggestive of hypersensitivity associated with administration of dobutamine including skin rash, fever, eosinophilia, and bronchospasm, have been reported occasionally. 
 Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection contains sodium bisulfite, a sulfite that may cause allergic-type reactions, including anaphylactic symptoms and life-threatening or less severe asthmatic episodes, in certain susceptible people. The overall prevalence of sulfite sensitivity in the general population is unknown and probably low. Sulfite sensitivity is seen more frequently in asthmatic than in nonasthmatic people. 
 Solutions containing dextrose should not be administered through the same administration set as blood, as this may result in pseudoagglutination or hemolysis. 
 The intravenous administration of solutions may cause fluid overloading resulting in dilution of serum electrolyte concentrations, overhydration, congested states or pulmonary edema. The risk of dilutional states is inversely proportional to the electrolyte concentrations of the injections. The risk of solute overload causing congested states with peripheral and pulmonary edema is directly proportional to the electrolyte concentration of the injections. 
 Excess administration of potassium-free solutions may result in significant hypokalemia.</Section>
<Section name="PRECAUTIONS SECTION" id="42232-9">
PRECAUTIONS 

 General 

 During the administration of Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection, as with any adrenergic agent, ECG and blood pressure should be continuously monitored. In addition, pulmonary wedge pressure and cardiac output should be monitored whenever possible to aid in the safe and effective infusion of dobutamine. 

 Hypovolemia should be corrected with suitable volume expanders before treatment with dobutamine is instituted. 
 Animal studies indicate that dobutamine may be ineffective if the patient has recently received a beta-blocking drug. In such a case, the peripheral vascular resistance may increase. 
 No improvement may be observed in the presence of marked mechanical obstruction, such as severe valvular aortic stenosis. 
 Solutions containing dextrose should be used with caution in patients with known subclinical or overt diabetes mellitus. 
 Do not administer unless solution is clear and seal is intact. 
 If administration is controlled by a pumping device, care must be taken to discontinue pumping action before the container runs dry or air embolism may result. 

 Usage Following Acute Myocardial Infarction 

 Clinical experience with dobutamine following myocardial infarction has been insufficient to establish the safety of the drug for this use. There is concern that any agent that increases contractile force and heart rate may increase the size of an infarction by intensifying ischemia, but it is not known whether dobutamine does so. 

 Drug Interactions 

 There was no evidence of drug interactions in clinical studies in which dobutamine was administered concurrently with other drugs, including digitalis preparations, furosemide, spironolactone, lidocaine, glyceryl trinitrate, isosorbide dinitrate, morphine, atropine, heparin, protamine, potassium chloride, folic acid, and acetaminophen. Preliminary studies indicate that the concomitant use of dobutamine and nitroprusside results in a higher cardiac output and, usually, a lower pulmonary wedge pressure than when either drug is used alone. 

 Carcinogenesis, Mutagenesis, Impairment of Fertility 

 Studies to evaluate the carcinogenic or mutagenic potential of dobutamine or the potential of the drug to affect fertility adversely have not been performed. 

 Pregnancy 

 Reproduction studies performed in rats and rabbits have revealed no evidence of harm to the fetus due to dobutamine. The drug, however, has not been administered to pregnant women and should be used only when the expected benefits clearly outweigh the potential risks to the fetus. 

 Pediatric Use 

 Dobutamine has been shown to increase cardiac output and systemic pressure in pediatric patients of every age group. In premature neonates, however, dobutamine is less effective than dopamine in raising systemic blood pressure without causing undue tachycardia, and dobutamine has not been shown to provide any added benefit when given to such infants already receiving optimal infusions of dopamine. 

 Geriatric Use 

 Clinical studies of dobutamine injection did not include sufficient numbers of subjects aged 65 and over to determine whether they respond differently from younger subjects. Other reported clinical experience has not identified differences in responses between the elderly and younger patients. In general, dose selection for an elderly patient should be cautious, usually starting at the low end of the dosing range, reflecting the greater frequency of decreased hepatic, renal, or cardiac function, and of concomitant disease or drug therapy.</Section>
<Section name="DOSAGE &amp; ADMINISTRATION SECTION" id="34068-7">
DOSAGE AND ADMINISTRATION 

 Recommended Dosage 

 Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection is administered intravenously through a suitable intravenous catheter or needle. A calibrated electronic infusion device is recommended for controlling the rate of flow in mL/hour or drops/minute. 
 Infusion of dobutamine should be started at a low rate (0.5-1.0 mcg/kg/min) and titrated at intervals of a few minutes, guided by the patient’s response, including systemic blood pressure, urine flow, frequency of ectopic activity, heart rate, and (whenever possible) measurements of cardiac output, central venous pressure, and/or pulmonary capillary wedge pressure. In reported trials, the optimal infusion rates have varied from patient to patient, usually 2-20 mcg/kg/min but sometimes slightly outside of this range. On rare occasions, infusion rates up to 40 mcg/kg/min have been required to obtain the desired effect. 
 Rates of infusion in mL/hour for dobutamine hydrochloride concentrations of 1,000, 2,000 and 4,000 mcg/mL are in Table 2. 
 This container system may be inappropriate for the dosage requirements of pediatric patients under 30 kg. Other dosage forms may be more appropriate. 
 Parenteral drug products should be inspected visually for particulate matter and discoloration prior to administration whenever solution and container permit. 
 Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection solutions may exhibit a pink color that, if present, will increase with time. This color change is due to slight oxidation of the drug, but there is no significant loss of potency. 
 The rate of administration and the duration of therapy should be adjusted according to the patient’s response, as determined by heart rate, presence of ectopic activity, blood pressure, urine flow, and, whenever possible, measurement of central venous or pulmonary wedge pressure and cardiac output. 
 Do not add supplementary medications to Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection. Do not administer Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5% Dextrose Injection simultaneously with solutions containing sodium bicarbonate or strong alkaline solutions.</Section>
</Text><Sentences>
<Sentence id="281" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>Do not administer Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5 %   Dextrose Injection simultaneously with solutions containing sodium bicarbonate or strong alkaline solutions .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M3" type="Trigger" span="0 17" str="Do not administer"/>
<Mention id="M2" type="Precipitant" span="112 18" str="sodium bicarbonate" code="N0000005741"/>
<Mention id="M4" type="Precipitant" span="134 25" str="strong alkaline solutions" code="NO MAP"/>
<Interaction id="I1" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M3" precipitant="M2"/>
<Interaction id="I2" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M3" precipitant="M4"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="281" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>Do not administer Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5 %   Dextrose Injection simultaneously with solutions containing sodium bicarbonate or strong alkaline solutions .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M7" type="Trigger" span="0 17" str="Do not administer"/>
<Mention id="M6" type="Precipitant" span="112 18" str="sodium bicarbonate" code="N0000005741"/>
<Mention id="M8" type="Precipitant" span="134 25" str="strong alkaline solutions" code="NO MAP"/>
<Interaction id="I3" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M7" precipitant="M6"/>
<Interaction id="I4" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M7" precipitant="M8"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="282" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5 %   Dextrose Injection solutions may exhibit a pink color that , if present , will increase with time .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="283" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5 %   Dextrose Injection contains sodium bisulfite , a sulfite that may cause allergic-type reactions , including anaphylactic symptoms and life-threatening or less severe asthmatic episodes , in certain susceptible people .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="284" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="34071-1">
<SentenceText>In patients who have atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response , a digitalis preparation should be used prior to institution of therapy with Dobutamine in D5W .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="285" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>During the administration of Dobutamine Hydrochloride in 5 %   Dextrose Injection , as with any adrenergic agent , ECG and blood pressure should be continuously monitored .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="286" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Hypovolemia should be corrected with suitable volume expanders before treatment with dobutamine is instituted .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="287" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>In premature neonates , however , dobutamine is less effective than dopamine in raising systemic blood pressure without causing undue tachycardia , and dobutamine has not been shown to provide any added benefit when given to such infants already receiving optimal infusions of dopamine .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="288" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>Preliminary studies indicate that the concomitant use of dobutamine and nitroprusside results in a higher cardiac output and , usually , a lower pulmonary wedge pressure than when either drug is used alone .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M9" type="Trigger" span="86 10" str="results in"/>
<Mention id="M10" type="Precipitant" span="72 13" str="nitroprusside" code="N0000006680"/>
<Mention id="M11" type="SpecificInteraction" span="99 21" str="higher cardiac output " code="27545003: Increased cardiac output (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M12" type="SpecificInteraction" span="139 30" str=" lower pulmonary wedge pressure" code=" 55973006: Decreased pulmonary arterial wedge pressure (finding)"/>
<Interaction id="I5" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M9" precipitant="M10" effect="M11;M12"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="289" LabelDrug="Dobutamine Hydrochloride in Dextrose" section="42232-9">
<SentenceText>There was no evidence of drug interactions in clinical studies in which dobutamine was administered concurrently with other drugs , including digitalis preparations , furosemide , spironolactone , lidocaine , glyceryl trinitrate , isosorbide dinitrate , morphine , atropine , heparin , protamine , potassium chloride , folic acid , and acetaminophen .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
</Sentences>
<LabelInteractions><LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="sodium bicarbonate" precipitantCode="N0000005741"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="strong alkaline solutions" precipitantCode="NO MAP"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="nitroprusside" precipitantCode="N0000006680" effect=" 55973006: Decreased pulmonary arterial wedge pressure (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="nitroprusside" precipitantCode="N0000006680" effect="27545003: Increased cardiac output (finding)"/>

</LabelInteractions></Label>