<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Label drug="Integrilin" setid="5ad82e30-50d8-450c-8a2a-b4b507ed1ce2">
<Text><Section name="DOSAGE &amp; ADMINISTRATION SECTION" id="34068-7">
2 DOSAGE AND ADMINISTRATION 

 Before infusion of INTEGRILIN, the following laboratory tests should be performed to identify pre-existing hemostatic abnormalities: hematocrit or hemoglobin, platelet count, serum creatinine, and PT/aPTT. In patients undergoing PCI, the activated clotting time (ACT) should also be measured. 
 The activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) should be maintained between 50 and 70 seconds unless PCI is to be performed. In patients treated with heparin, bleeding can be minimized by close monitoring of the aPTT and ACT. 

 ACS or PCI: 180 mcg/kg IV bolus as soon as possible after diagnosis followed by infusion at 2 mcg/kg/min. ( 2.1 , 2.2 ) 
 PCI: Add a second 180 mcg/kg bolus at 10 minutes. ( 2.2 ) 
 In patients with creatinine clearance less than 50 mL/min, reduce the infusion to 1 mcg/kg/min. ( 2.1 , 2.2 , 2.3 ) 

 2.1 Dosage in Acute Coronary Syndrome (ACS) 

 Indication 
 Normal Renal Function 
 Creatinine Clearance less than 50 mL/min 

 Patients with ACS 
 180 mcg/kg intravenous (IV) bolus as soon as possible after diagnosis, followed by continuous infusion of 2 mcg/kg/min 
 180 mcg/kg IV bolus as soon as possible after diagnosis, followed by continuous infusion of 1 mcg/kg/min 

 Infusion should continue until hospital discharge or initiation of coronary artery bypass graft surgery (CABG), up to 72 hours 
 If a patient is to undergo PCI, the infusion should be continued until hospital discharge or for up to 18 to 24 hours after the procedure, whichever comes first, allowing for up to 96 hours of therapy 
 Aspirin, 160 to 325 mg, should be given daily 

 INTEGRILIN should be given concomitantly with heparin dosed to achieve the following parameters: 

 During Medical Management : Target aPTT 50 to 70 seconds 
 If weight greater than or equal to 70 kg, 5000-unit bolus followed by infusion of 1000 units/h. 
 If weight less than 70 kg, 60-units/kg bolus followed by infusion of 12 units/kg/h. 

 During PCI : Target ACT 200 to 300 seconds 
 If heparin is initiated prior to PCI, additional boluses during PCI to maintain an ACT target of 200 to 300 seconds. 
 Heparin infusion after the PCI is discouraged. 

 2.2 Dosage in Percutaneous Coronary Intervention (PCI) 

 Indication 
 Normal Renal Function 
 Creatinine Clearance less than 50 mL/min 

 Patients with PCI 
 180 mcg/kg IV bolus immediately before PCI followed by continuous infusion of 2 mcg/kg/min and a second bolus of 180 mcg/kg (given 10 minutes after the first bolus) 
 180 mcg/kg IV bolus immediately before PCI followed by continuous infusion of 1 mcg/kg/min and a second bolus of 180 mcg/kg (given 10 minutes after the first bolus) 

 Infusion should be continued until hospital discharge, or for up to 18 to 24 hours, whichever comes first. A minimum of 12 hours of infusion is recommended. 
 In patients who undergo CABG surgery, INTEGRILIN infusion should be discontinued prior to surgery. 
 Aspirin, 160 to 325 mg, should be given 1 to 24 hours prior to PCI and daily thereafter 

 INTEGRILIN should be given concomitantly with heparin to achieve a target ACT of 200 to 300 seconds. Administer 60-units/kg bolus initially in patients not treated with heparin within 6 hours prior to PCI. 
 Additional boluses during PCI to maintain ACT within target. 
 Heparin infusion after the PCI is strongly discouraged. 

 Patients requiring thrombolytic therapy should discontinue INTEGRILIN. 

 2.3 Important Administration Instructions 

 Inspect INTEGRILIN for particulate matter and discoloration prior to administration, whenever solution and container permit. 
 May administer INTEGRILIN in the same intravenous line as alteplase, atropine, dobutamine, heparin, lidocaine, meperidine, metoprolol, midazolam, morphine, nitroglycerin, or verapamil. Do not administer INTEGRILIN through the same intravenous line as furosemide. 
 May administer INTEGRILIN in the same IV line with 0.9% NaCl or 0.9% NaCl/5% dextrose. With either vehicle, the infusion may also contain up to 60 mEq/L of potassium chloride. 
 Withdraw the bolus dose(s) of INTEGRILIN from the 10-mL vial into a syringe. Administer the bolus dose(s) by IV push. 
 Immediately following the bolus dose administration, initiate a continuous infusion of INTEGRILIN. When using an intravenous infusion pump, administer INTEGRILIN undiluted directly from the 100-mL vial. Spike the 100-mL vial with a vented infusion set. Center the spike within the circle on the stopper top. 
 Discard any unused portion left in the vial. 

 Administer INTEGRILIN by volume according to patient weight (see Table 1 ). 

 Table 1: INTEGRILIN Dosing Charts by Weight 

 Patient Weight 
 180-mcg/kg Bolus Volume 
 2-mcg/kg/min Infusion Volume (CrCl greater than or equal to 50 mL/min) 
 1-mcg/kg/min Infusion Volume (CrCl less than 50 mL/min) 

 (kg) 

 (lb) 

 (from 2-mg/mL vial) 

 (from 2-mg/mL 100-mL vial) 

 (from 0.75-mg/mL 100-mL vial) 

 (from 2-mg/mL 100-mL vial) 

 (from 0.75-mg/mL 100-mL vial) 

 37-41 
 81-91 
 3.4 mL 
 2 mL/h 
 6 mL/h 
 1 mL/h 
 3 mL/h 

 42-46 
 92-102 
 4 mL 
 2.5 mL/h 
 7 mL/h 
 1.3 mL/h 
 3.5 mL/h 

 47-53 
 103-117 
 4.5 mL 
 3 mL/h 
 8 mL/h 
 1.5 mL/h 
 4 mL/h 

 54-59 
 118-130 
 5 mL 
 3.5 mL/h 
 9 mL/h 
 1.8 mL/h 
 4.5 mL/h 

 60-65 
 131-143 
 5.6 mL 
 3.8 mL/h 
 10 mL/h 
 1.9 mL/h 
 5 mL/h 

 66-71 
 144-157 
 6.2 mL 
 4 mL/h 
 11 mL/h 
 2 mL/h 
 5.5 mL/h 

 72-78 
 158-172 
 6.8 mL 
 4.5 mL/h 
 12 mL/h 
 2.3 mL/h 
 6 mL/h 

 79-84 
 173-185 
 7.3 mL 
 5 mL/h 
 13 mL/h 
 2.5 mL/h 
 6.5 mL/h 

 85-90 
 186-198 
 7.9 mL 
 5.3 mL/h 
 14 mL/h 
 2.7 mL/h 
 7 mL/h 

 91-96 
 199-212 
 8.5 mL 
 5.6 mL/h 
 15 mL/h 
 2.8 mL/h 
 7.5 mL/h 

 97-103 
 213-227 
 9 mL 
 6 mL/h 
 16 mL/h 
 3.0 mL/h 
 8 mL/h 

 104-109 
 228-240 
 9.5 mL 
 6.4 mL/h 
 17 mL/h 
 3.2 mL/h 
 8.5 mL/h 

 110-115 
 241-253 
 10.2 mL 
 6.8 mL/h 
 18 mL/h 
 3.4 mL/h 
 9 mL/h 

 116-121 
 254-267 
 10.7 mL 
 7 mL/h 
 19 mL/h 
 3.5 mL/h 
 9.5 mL/h 

 &gt;121 
 &gt;267 
 11.3 mL 
 7.5 mL/h 
 20 mL/h 
 3.7 mL/h 
 10 mL/h</Section>
<Section name="CONTRAINDICATIONS SECTION" id="34070-3">
4 CONTRAINDICATIONS 

 Treatment with INTEGRILIN is contraindicated in patients with: 

 A history of bleeding diathesis, or evidence of active abnormal bleeding within the previous 30 days 
 Severe hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt;200 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mm Hg) not adequately controlled on antihypertensive therapy 
 Major surgery within the preceding 6 weeks 
 History of stroke within 30 days or any history of hemorrhagic stroke 
 Current or planned administration of another parenteral GP IIb/IIIa inhibitor 
 Dependency on renal dialysis 
 Hypersensitivity to INTEGRILIN or any component of the product (hypersensitivity reactions that occurred included anaphylaxis and urticaria). 

 Bleeding diathesis or bleeding within the previous 30 days ( 4 ) 
 Severe uncontrolled hypertension ( 4 ) 
 Major surgery within the preceding 6 weeks ( 4 ) 
 Stroke within 30 days or any history of hemorrhagic stroke ( 4 ) 
 Coadministration of another parenteral GP IIb/IIIa inhibitor ( 4 ) 
 Dependency on renal dialysis ( 4 ) 
 Known hypersensitivity to any component of the product ( 4 )</Section>
<Section name="WARNINGS AND PRECAUTIONS SECTION" id="43685-7">
5 WARNINGS AND PRECAUTIONS 

 INTEGRILIN can cause serious bleeding. If bleeding cannot be controlled, discontinue INTEGRILIN immediately. Minimize vascular and other traumas. If heparin is given concomitantly, monitor aPTT or ACT. ( 5.1 ) 
 Thrombocytopenia: Discontinue INTEGRILIN and heparin. Monitor and treat condition appropriately. ( 5.2 ) 

 5.1 Bleeding 

 Bleeding is the most common complication encountered during INTEGRILIN therapy. Administration of INTEGRILIN is associated with an increase in major and minor bleeding, as classified by the criteria of the Thrombolysis in Myocardial Infarction Study group (TIMI) [see Adverse Reactions (6.1) ] . Most major bleeding associated with INTEGRILIN has been at the arterial access site for cardiac catheterization or from the gastrointestinal or genitourinary tract. Minimize the use of arterial and venous punctures, intramuscular injections, and the use of urinary catheters, nasotracheal intubation, and nasogastric tubes. When obtaining intravenous access, avoid non-compressible sites (e.g., subclavian or jugular veins). 

 Use of Thrombolytics, Anticoagulants, and Other Antiplatelet Agents 

 Risk factors for bleeding include older age, a history of bleeding disorders, and concomitant use of drugs that increase the risk of bleeding (thrombolytics, oral anticoagulants, nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, and P2Y 12 inhibitors). Concomitant treatment with other inhibitors of platelet receptor glycoprotein (GP) IIb/IIIa should be avoided. In patients treated with heparin, bleeding can be minimized by close monitoring of the aPTT and ACT [see Dosage and Administration (2) ] . 

 Care of the Femoral Artery Access Site in Patients Undergoing Percutaneous Coronary Intervention (PCI) 

 In patients undergoing PCI, treatment with INTEGRILIN is associated with an increase in major and minor bleeding at the site of arterial sheath placement. After PCI, INTEGRILIN infusion should be continued until hospital discharge or up to 18 to 24 hours, whichever comes first. Heparin use is discouraged after the PCI procedure. Early sheath removal is encouraged while INTEGRILIN is being infused. Prior to removing the sheath, it is recommended that heparin be discontinued for 3 to 4 hours and an aPTT of &lt;45 seconds or ACT &lt;150 seconds be achieved. In any case, both heparin and INTEGRILIN should be discontinued and sheath hemostasis should be achieved at least 2 to 4 hours before hospital discharge. If bleeding at access site cannot be controlled with pressure, infusion of INTEGRILIN and heparin should be discontinued immediately. 

 5.2 Thrombocytopenia 

 There have been reports of acute, profound thrombocytopenia (immune-mediated and non-immune mediated) with INTEGRILIN. In the event of acute profound thrombocytopenia or a confirmed platelet decrease to &lt;100,000/mm 3 , discontinue INTEGRILIN and heparin (unfractionated or low-molecular weight). Monitor serial platelet counts, assess the presence of drug-dependent antibodies, and treat as appropriate [see Adverse Reactions (6.1) ] . 
 There has been no clinical experience with INTEGRILIN initiated in patients with a baseline platelet count &lt;100,000/mm 3 . If a patient with low platelet counts is receiving INTEGRILIN, their platelet count should be monitored closely.</Section>
<Section name="DRUG INTERACTIONS SECTION" id="34073-7">
7 DRUG INTERACTIONS 

 Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding. Avoid concomitant use with other glycoprotein (GP) IIb/IIIa inhibitors. ( 7.1 ) 

 7.1 Use of Thrombolytics, Anticoagulants, and Other Antiplatelet Agents 

 Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding. Concomitant treatment with other inhibitors of platelet receptor GP IIb/IIIa should be avoided.</Section>
</Text><Sentences>
<Sentence id="231" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>Before infusion of INTEGRILIN , the following laboratory tests should be performed to identify pre-existing hemostatic abnormalities : hematocrit or hemoglobin , platelet count , serum creatinine , and PT/aPTT .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="232" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>Do not administer INTEGRILIN through the same intravenous line as furosemide .</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M1" type="Trigger" span="0 17" str="Do not administer"/>
<Mention id="M2" type="Precipitant" span="66 10" str="furosemide" code="N0000007175"/>
<Interaction id="I1" type="Unspecified interaction" trigger="M1" precipitant="M2"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="233" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>INTEGRILIN should be given concomitantly with heparin dosed to achieve the following parameters : .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="234" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>INTEGRILIN should be given concomitantly with heparin to achieve a target ACT of 200 to 300 seconds .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="235" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>May administer INTEGRILIN in the same intravenous line as alteplase , atropine , dobutamine , heparin , lidocaine , meperidine , metoprolol , midazolam , morphine , nitroglycerin , or verapamil .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="236" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34068-7">
<SentenceText>May administer INTEGRILIN in the same IV line with 0.9 % NaCl or 0.9 % NaCl/5 % dextrose .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="237" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>(7.1) Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M15" type="Trigger" span="102 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M4" type="Precipitant" span="26 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M5" type="SpecificInteraction" span="102 30" str="increases the risk of bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M7" type="Precipitant" span="71 7" str="aspirin" code="N0000006582"/>
<Mention id="M17" type="SpecificInteraction" span="124 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M10" type="Precipitant" span="62 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M13" type="Precipitant" span="92 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M16" type="Precipitant" span="47 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I2" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M4" effect="M5"/>
<Interaction id="I3" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M7" effect="M17"/>
<Interaction id="I4" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M10" effect="M17"/>
<Interaction id="I5" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M13" effect="M17"/>
<Interaction id="I6" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M15" precipitant="M16" effect="M17"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="237" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>(7.1) Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M30" type="Trigger" span="102 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M19" type="Precipitant" span="26 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M20" type="SpecificInteraction" span="102 30" str="increases the risk of bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M22" type="Precipitant" span="71 7" str="aspirin" code="N0000006582"/>
<Mention id="M32" type="SpecificInteraction" span="124 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M25" type="Precipitant" span="62 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M28" type="Precipitant" span="92 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M31" type="Precipitant" span="47 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I7" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M30" precipitant="M19" effect="M20"/>
<Interaction id="I8" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M30" precipitant="M22" effect="M32"/>
<Interaction id="I9" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M30" precipitant="M25" effect="M32"/>
<Interaction id="I10" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M30" precipitant="M28" effect="M32"/>
<Interaction id="I11" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M30" precipitant="M31" effect="M32"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="237" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>(7.1) Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M45" type="Trigger" span="102 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M34" type="Precipitant" span="26 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M35" type="SpecificInteraction" span="102 30" str="increases the risk of bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M37" type="Precipitant" span="71 7" str="aspirin" code="N0000006582"/>
<Mention id="M47" type="SpecificInteraction" span="124 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M40" type="Precipitant" span="62 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M43" type="Precipitant" span="92 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M46" type="Precipitant" span="47 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I12" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M45" precipitant="M34" effect="M35"/>
<Interaction id="I13" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M45" precipitant="M37" effect="M47"/>
<Interaction id="I14" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M45" precipitant="M40" effect="M47"/>
<Interaction id="I15" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M45" precipitant="M43" effect="M47"/>
<Interaction id="I16" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M45" precipitant="M46" effect="M47"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="237" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>(7.1) Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M60" type="Trigger" span="102 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M49" type="Precipitant" span="26 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M50" type="SpecificInteraction" span="102 30" str="increases the risk of bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M52" type="Precipitant" span="71 7" str="aspirin" code="N0000006582"/>
<Mention id="M62" type="SpecificInteraction" span="124 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M55" type="Precipitant" span="62 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M58" type="Precipitant" span="92 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M61" type="Precipitant" span="47 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I17" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M60" precipitant="M49" effect="M50"/>
<Interaction id="I18" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M60" precipitant="M52" effect="M62"/>
<Interaction id="I19" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M60" precipitant="M55" effect="M62"/>
<Interaction id="I20" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M60" precipitant="M58" effect="M62"/>
<Interaction id="I21" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M60" precipitant="M61" effect="M62"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="237" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>(7.1) Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M75" type="Trigger" span="102 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M64" type="Precipitant" span="26 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M65" type="SpecificInteraction" span="102 30" str="increases the risk of bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M67" type="Precipitant" span="71 7" str="aspirin" code="N0000006582"/>
<Mention id="M77" type="SpecificInteraction" span="124 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M70" type="Precipitant" span="62 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M73" type="Precipitant" span="92 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M76" type="Precipitant" span="47 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I22" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M75" precipitant="M64" effect="M65"/>
<Interaction id="I23" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M75" precipitant="M67" effect="M77"/>
<Interaction id="I24" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M75" precipitant="M70" effect="M77"/>
<Interaction id="I25" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M75" precipitant="M73" effect="M77"/>
<Interaction id="I26" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M75" precipitant="M76" effect="M77"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="238" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Avoid concomitant use with other glycoprotein (GP) IIb/IIIa inhibitors.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="239" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M87" type="Trigger" span="96 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M79" type="Precipitant" span="20 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M89" type="SpecificInteraction" span="118 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M82" type="Precipitant" span="56 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M85" type="Precipitant" span="86 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M88" type="Precipitant" span="41 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I27" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M87" precipitant="M79" effect="M89"/>
<Interaction id="I28" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M87" precipitant="M82" effect="M89"/>
<Interaction id="I29" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M87" precipitant="M85" effect="M89"/>
<Interaction id="I30" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M87" precipitant="M88" effect="M89"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="239" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M99" type="Trigger" span="96 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M91" type="Precipitant" span="20 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M101" type="SpecificInteraction" span="118 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M94" type="Precipitant" span="56 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M97" type="Precipitant" span="86 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M100" type="Precipitant" span="41 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I31" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M99" precipitant="M91" effect="M101"/>
<Interaction id="I32" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M99" precipitant="M94" effect="M101"/>
<Interaction id="I33" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M99" precipitant="M97" effect="M101"/>
<Interaction id="I34" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M99" precipitant="M100" effect="M101"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="239" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M111" type="Trigger" span="96 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M103" type="Precipitant" span="20 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M113" type="SpecificInteraction" span="118 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M106" type="Precipitant" span="56 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M109" type="Precipitant" span="86 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M112" type="Precipitant" span="41 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I35" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M111" precipitant="M103" effect="M113"/>
<Interaction id="I36" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M111" precipitant="M106" effect="M113"/>
<Interaction id="I37" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M111" precipitant="M109" effect="M113"/>
<Interaction id="I38" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M111" precipitant="M112" effect="M113"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="239" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Coadministration of antiplatelet agents, thrombolytics, heparin, aspirin, and chronic NSAID use increases the risk of bleeding.</SentenceText>
<Mention id="M123" type="Trigger" span="96 18" str="increases the risk"/>
<Mention id="M115" type="Precipitant" span="20 19" str="antiplatelet agents" code="N0000175578"/>
<Mention id="M125" type="SpecificInteraction" span="118 8" str="bleeding" code="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<Mention id="M118" type="Precipitant" span="56 7" str="heparin" code="N0000006341"/>
<Mention id="M121" type="Precipitant" span="86 5" str="NSAID" code="N0000175722"/>
<Mention id="M124" type="Precipitant" span="41 13" str="thrombolytics" code="N0000029298"/>
<Interaction id="I39" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M123" precipitant="M115" effect="M125"/>
<Interaction id="I40" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M123" precipitant="M118" effect="M125"/>
<Interaction id="I41" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M123" precipitant="M121" effect="M125"/>
<Interaction id="I42" type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" trigger="M123" precipitant="M124" effect="M125"/>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="240" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="34073-7">
<SentenceText>Concomitant treatment with other inhibitors of platelet receptor GP IIb/IIIa should be avoided.</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="241" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="43685-7">
<SentenceText>If bleeding at access site can not be controlled with pressure , infusion of INTEGRILIN and heparin should be discontinued immediately .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="242" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="43685-7">
<SentenceText>In any case , both heparin and INTEGRILIN should be discontinued and sheath hemostasis should be achieved at least 2 to 4 hours before hospital discharge .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="243" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="43685-7">
<SentenceText>In the event of acute profound thrombocytopenia or a confirmed platelet decrease to 100,000 / mm3 , discontinue INTEGRILIN and heparin ( unfractionated or low-molecular weight ) .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
<Sentence id="244" LabelDrug="Integrilin" section="43685-7">
<SentenceText>Thrombocytopenia : Discontinue INTEGRILIN and heparin .</SentenceText>
</Sentence>
</Sentences>
<LabelInteractions><LabelInteraction type="Unspecified interaction" precipitant="furosemide" precipitantCode="N0000007175"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="antiplatelet agents" precipitantCode="N0000175578" effect="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="aspirin" precipitantCode="N0000006582" effect="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="heparin" precipitantCode="N0000006341" effect="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="nsaid" precipitantCode="N0000175722" effect="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>
<LabelInteraction type="Pharmacodynamic interaction" precipitant="thrombolytics" precipitantCode="N0000029298" effect="131148009: Bleeding (finding)"/>

</LabelInteractions></Label>